Beck Piscopo

Data Product Engineer

beckpiscopo.xyz x: @beckpiscopo • Cabarete, DR People often describe me as relentless and meticulous. While this brings both advantages and challenges, I'm looking for a company where my unique disposition is an asset. I am highly analytical, thrive in ambiguity, and am unusually self-directed. After a two-year sabbatical raising my son and sailing the Caribbean, we're settling back on land for preschool. The experience made me more resourceful, resilient, and adaptable. I care about privacy-by-design and building products that protect individual autonomy while strengthening collective agency.

Work Experience

Data Analyst | BI Engineer

First Orion, 2019-2023

- Routinely analyzed billions of call records to research fraud patterns, detect anomalies, and troubleshoot the in-network solution
- Acted as technical account manager for a solution that generated \$4M+ in annual revenue, served as the subject matter expert among engineers, analysts, and executives
- Led the development of a custom sentiment analysis algorithm that outperformed the existing vendor solution by 30%
- Designed and implemented a fully automated KPI/SLA reporting pipeline for the CNAM (Caller ID Name) platform using Python, SQL, and Spark
- Lead monthly stakeholder meetings for both First Orion and T-Mobile
- Architected an internal BI platform to increase data access and reduce time-to-insight for analysts, sales engineers, and customer support teams

Jr. Developer | Assoc. Project Manager

Team SI, 2019-2019

- Gathered requirements from clients on website needs
- Assisted with project management tasks
- Contributed to the development of client websites
- Assisted a Senior developer in building an integration between Azure DevOps and Google Hangouts Chat using JavaScript, an Azure Function, and ngrok

Tech & Brand Strategist

The Green Corner Store, 2016-2018

- Assisted in cultivating a brand identity, strategy, and vision
- · Maintained a weekly newsletter
- Managed all social media accounts
- Analyzed sales data, set KPIs, measured progress
- Wrote the employee handbook and business proposals
- Managed a small team of employees

Skills

Technical Skills

- Exploratory Data Analysis
- Statistical Modeling
- ETL Pipeline Automation
- Dashboard Development
- Web Scraping
- API Development
- Requirements Gathering
- Stakeholder Communication
- Prompt Engineering

Tools

- Databricks Notebooks
- Apache Spark / Spark SQL
- Tableau
- Flipside Analytics
- AWS (Athena & Redshift)
- PostgreSQL
- MySQL
- MongoDB

Languages

- Scala
- Python
- SQL
- JavaScript

Education

BS, Information Science
University of Arkansas at Little Rock
Aug 2014 - Dec 2018